<docstrings>

<override namespace="ensight.batch">
<description>
Detect if EnSight is running in batch mode::

    ensight.batch() -> int


Returns:
    If EnSight is running in batch mode, this function returns 1.

</description>
</override>

<override namespace="ensight.objs.next_id">
<description>
Return the object id of the next object EnSight will allocate::

    ensight.objs.next_id() -> int


All EnSight objects have a unique object ID.  These IDs are monotonically increasing.
This function returns the id number that EnSight will assign to the next object that
it creates.  It can be used to detect if an object is new, relative to when this function
is called.


Returns:
    The ENSOBJ object id of the next allocated object.

</description>
</override>

<override namespace="ensight.objs.wrap_id">
<description>
Return the Python proxy object for a specific EnSight object id::

    ensight.objs.wrap_id(id: int) -> ENSOBJ


The EnSight Python object interface uses proxy objects.  This method creates
a proxy object associated with a given object id.  If the specified id does
not exist, a RuntimeError exception is raised.

Args:
    id:
        An object id number.


Returns:
    The ENSOBJ proxy object associated with the specified id.

</description>
</override>

<override namespace="ensight.objs.valid_id">
<description>
Check to see if a given id corresponds to an existing EnSight object::

    ensight.objs.valid_id(id: int) -> bool


Args:
    id:
        An object id number.


Returns:
    True if the EnSight object with the passed id currently exists.

</description>
</override>

<override namespace="ensight.objs.enum_to_name">
<description>
Convert an attribute id into the associated string name::

    ensight.objs.enum_to_name(attrid: int) -> str


For a given attribute id, return the ASCII name of the
attribute.  If the input id is not a valid attribute,
a RuntimeError will be raised.


Args:
    attrid:
        An attribute id number.


Returns:
    The string name for the attribute number.

Example:
    ::

        ensight.objs.enum_to_name(1610613151)
        'NODEVARIABLE'

</description>
</override>

</docstrings>